<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Long Head</title>
    <link>https://greg.langmead.info/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Long Head</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://greg.langmead.info/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Research and writing</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/writing/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 21:06:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/publications/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/cv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;greg-langmead-phd&#34;&gt;Greg Langmead, Ph.D.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a teammate and leader, mathematician and engineer, researcher and
developer of shipping products. I want to give back and have an impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Successful leader, individual contributor, and collaborator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long and successful track record integrating research into products&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ph.D. in mathematics, in four-dimensional geometry and mathematical
physics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machine learning, natural language processing, Java, Python, Spark,
Swift&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recent second mathematical career in homotopy type theory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good listener, eager to teach and learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;education&#34;&gt;Education&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA &amp;mdash; M.S. Philosophy, expected 2024.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Columbia University, New York, NY &amp;mdash; Ph.D Mathematics, 2001.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Columbia University, New York, NY &amp;mdash; B.A., Mathematics and Astrophysics, Magna cum Laude, 1994.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;experience&#34;&gt;Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;apple-inc-pittsburgh-pa-----2011--present&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple Inc., Pittsburgh, PA &amp;mdash; 2011&amp;ndash;Present&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;machine-learning-manager-services-june-2024&#34;&gt;Machine Learning Manager, Services, June 2024&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manager of Apple News algorithms design team. Our team of scientist-engineers
develop algorithmic aspects of the user experience in News and Stocks, such as:
on-device personalization, semantic understanding of text, deduplication of
same-fact news stories. We collaborate at the intersection of technology and
liberal arts, working with designers, journalists, app engineers, and backend
operations engineers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;machine-learning-engineer-services-january-2014&#34;&gt;Machine Learning Engineer, Services, January 2014&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founding member of Apple News algorithms team starting 2014. Designed
and built entity linking and other algorithms to assign articles into
topic feeds in reader app. Supervised bring-up of other algorithms such
as clustering of articles and integration of heterogenous topic
taxonomies into knowledge base. Collaborator and catalyst for other
components including search and personalization. Continuous iteration on
accuracy of algorithms, expanding to Stocks app (2018) and French
(2019). Leader when assessing scope and deciding priorities. Good
intuition for fitting work to schedules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influential in maintaining a culture of transparency and accountability
via metrics and education. Advocate for demystifying our work and
maintaining close partnership with nontechnical teams such as editorial
and program management. Adapted ambient engineering culture to research
team. Vocal advocate for process changes. Generous with onboarding and
mentoring. Many positive comments in peer and manager feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;software-engineer-productivity-applications-july-2011&#34;&gt;Software Engineer, Productivity Applications, July 2011&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developed iOS and macOS iBooks Author software for authoring and reading multi-touch
books. Wrote Objective-C code, performed code reviews, and collaborated
with other internal groups through three release cycles including the
initial release of multi-touch features in January 2012. Designed and
pitched novel features and filed one patent application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sdl-language-technologies-los-angeles-ca-----oct-2004--july-2011&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SDL Language Technologies, Los Angeles, CA &amp;mdash; Oct 2004&amp;ndash;July 2011&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;manager-dec-2010--july-2011&#34;&gt;Manager, Dec 2010&amp;ndash;July 2011&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;senior-research-scientist-jan-2010--july-2011&#34;&gt;Senior Research Scientist, Jan 2010&amp;ndash;July 2011&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;research-scientist-july-2005--jan-2010&#34;&gt;Research Scientist, July 2005&amp;ndash;Jan 2010&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;senior-data-engineer-oct-2004--july-2005&#34;&gt;Senior Data Engineer, Oct 2004&amp;ndash;July 2005&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Led the development of the core learning workflows that underpinned
SDL&amp;rsquo;s statistical machine translation product line.
Provided leadership and vision for six years, transforming the workflow
from an academic research project to an internally-facing product. Grew
a team of five direct reports and several collaborators with an exciting
and engaged group culture and consistently high achievement in an Agile
development framework. Successfully implemented a strategy of continuous
integration of new research, enabling rapid commercialization in the
cutting-edge field of machine translation. Contributed key innovations
to enable complete parallelization of every component. Created a novel
meta-workflow platform to unify heterogeneous internal processes,
increasing operational efficiency, and permitting rapid integration of
new capabilities. Built and maintained a close relationship with IT to
integrate decision-making concerning workflow software with the
management of operating systems and capital investments in new hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Made original contributions to the field of statistical machine
translation in the areas of parallel processing, domain adaptation,
decoding with synchronous context-free grammars and integrated language
models, integration of statistical and rule-based components, and
named-entity translation. Co-authored academic conference papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managed and led Professional Services department through an important
transition from manual, error-prone processes to repeatable, scalable
and automated ones. Formed and maintained an interdepartmental
collaboration to gather requirements from Services group and implement
them rapidly in the workflow software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Served as Principal Investigator for several government projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;center-for-communications-research-princeton-nj-----june--aug-2004&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Center for Communications Research, Princeton, NJ &amp;mdash; June&amp;ndash;Aug 2004&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;adjunct-research-staff&#34;&gt;Adjunct Research Staff&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invited to join the Summer Conference on Applied Mathematical Problems.
Performed classified research in cryptology. Successfully combined
mathematical research and software engineering in a highly collaborative
environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;design-science-inc-long-beach-ca-----june-2001--oct-2004&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design Science, Inc., Long Beach, CA &amp;mdash; June 2001&amp;ndash;Oct 2004&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;product-manager&#34;&gt;Product Manager&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managed the release of three mathematical expression typesetting
products for Macintosh. Team included myself and three other developers.
Served as liaison with the Microsoft Office for Mac team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collaborated with teammate Robert Miner on math-aware search engine.
Modified Lucene open source document indexer with custom analyzer plugin
to index normalized MathML expressions. Part of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sbir.gov/sbirsearch/detail/145099&#34;&gt;an NSF SBIR
project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publications&#34;&gt;Publications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aclanthology.org/D10-1063/&#34;&gt;SCFG Decoding without
Binarization&lt;/a&gt;, M.
Hopkins, G. Langmead, Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods
in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), Cambridge, MA, 2010&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aclanthology.org/D09-1007/&#34;&gt;Cube Pruning as Heuristic
Search&lt;/a&gt;, M. Hopkins,
G. Langmead, Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in
Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), Singapore, 2009&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aclanthology.org/W11-2166/&#34;&gt;Extraction programs: a unified approach to translation rule
extraction&lt;/a&gt;, Mark
Hopkins, Greg Langmead, Tai Vo (2011). Proceedings of the Sixth Workshop
on Statistical Machine Translation, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/hep-th/0210192&#34;&gt;A Supersymmetric Quantum Field Theory Formulation of the Donaldson
Polynomial
Invariants&lt;/a&gt;, G.
Langmead, Ph.D. dissertation. Self-published to arxiv.org.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;patents&#34;&gt;Patents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Task parallelization in a text-to-text system&lt;/em&gt;, G. Langmead, K. Yamada,
K. Knight, D. Marcu, US patent
&lt;a href=&#34;https://patents.google.com/patent/US7389222B1/en?oq=7,389,222&#34;&gt;7,389,222&lt;/a&gt;,
to Language Weaver, Inc., Patent and Trademark Office, 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Adapter for allowing both online and offline training of a text to text
system&lt;/em&gt;, K. Yamada, K. Knight, G. Langmead, US patent
&lt;a href=&#34;https://patents.google.com/patent/US7624020B2/en?oq=7,624,020&#34;&gt;7,624,020&lt;/a&gt;,
to Language Weaver, Inc., Patent and Trademark Office, 2009.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;System and method for interacting with a displayed work space&lt;/em&gt;, Donald
R. Beaver, Gregory C. Langmead, US patent
&lt;a href=&#34;https://patents.google.com/patent/US9075519B2/en?oq=9,075,519&#34;&gt;9,075,519&lt;/a&gt;,
to Apple Inc., Patent and Trademark Office, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Personalization Aggregate Content Item Recommendations&lt;/em&gt;, Anil A.
Sewani, Collin D. Ruffenach, Dominic J. Hughes, Ian J. Elseth, Pushkaraj
Bhirud, Sidy Diop, Venkatesh Venkataramanan, Gregory C. Langmead,
Gurumurthy D. Ramkumar, US patent pending
&lt;a href=&#34;https://patents.google.com/patent/US20200301973A1/en?oq=16/821,832&#34;&gt;16/821,832&lt;/a&gt;,
to Apple Inc., Patent and Trademark Office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apparatus, system and method for string disambiguation and entity
ranking&lt;/em&gt;, Gregory C. Langmead, Dominic J. Hughes, Mark A. Gingrich, Ravi
Chandra Jammalamadaka, Donald R. Beaver, Shizhu Liu, Pushkaraj Bhirud,
Kamal M. Ali, Daniel Ribeiro Silva, Martin J. Murrett, US patent
&lt;a href=&#34;https://patents.google.com/patent/US10146775B2/en?oq=10,146,775&#34;&gt;10,146,775&lt;/a&gt;,
to Apple Inc., Patent and Trademark Office, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reader application with a personalized feed and method of providing
recommendations while maintaining user privacy&lt;/em&gt;, Martin J. Murrett, Ian
J. Elseth, Guillermo Ortiz, Ravi Chandra Jammalamadaka, Dominic J.
Hughes, Steve E. Marmon, Casey M. Dougherty, Gregory C. Langmead, Mark
A. Gingrich, Donald R. Beaver, Amogh Mahapatra, Collin D. Ruffenach,
Georgios Sofianatos, Justin W. Sung, Kang Tu, Jason A. Novak, US patent
&lt;a href=&#34;https://patents.google.com/patent/US10268747B2/en?oq=10,268,747&#34;&gt;10,268,747&lt;/a&gt;,
to Apple Inc., Patent and Trademark Office, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contact&#34;&gt;Contact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:glangmead@gmail.com&#34;&gt;glangmead@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://greg.langmead.info&#34;&gt;greg.langmead.info&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/glangmead&#34;&gt;github.com/glangmead&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;linkedin.com/in/glangmead&#34;&gt;linkedin.com/in/glangmead&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authors</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/authors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/authors/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
