<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Long Head</title>
    <link>https://greg.langmead.info/category/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Long Head</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 02:21:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://greg.langmead.info/category/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rubik&#39;s Cube</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2015-06-23-rubiks-cube/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 02:21:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2015-06-23-rubiks-cube/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided recently to embrace my dilettantism. I don&amp;rsquo;t think there have been two consecutive days in my life where I wanted to pursue and learn the same ideas. Now mind you, the complete list of topics is finite and I cycle back eventually.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the importance of mentors</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2008-07-10-on-the-importance-of-mentors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2008 04:10:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2008-07-10-on-the-importance-of-mentors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I grew up assuming that people make their own way in the world. I thought it was up to me to make every decision, plan every move, open every door, and find my own way in my life and career. Only much later did I learn that I was doing it all wrong. Not only is my way much harder, it&amp;rsquo;s also completely miserable to be so isolated. Here&amp;rsquo;s an example. The place where I started making these wrong decisions was in college. I attended my classes, which in some cases were way below my capabilities, and in other cases were way above. Either way, at the end of class, I packed up my things and walked back to my room. I dreamed of being a scientist, just like I had since I was 10 years old. But all I did was go to class, I never spoke with any professors, nor was I ever approached by any. My talents started to appear in my sophomore year, but I was still doing things in this retarded way. Then in my junior year the first consequence of my nihilistic lifestyle happened, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t even really notice it for what it was until years later. I switched my major from Astronomy to Astrophysics, then I added a concentration (minor) in Math, and then I made Math a second major. This all happened within a couple of months. Even these bureaucratic thrashings didn&amp;rsquo;t raise any red flags in any administrators or professors. No one cared. So, I shifted my focus to math, threw away the pile of physics grad school applications I had, and requested a bunch of math ones. I went to graduate school for a year at Stony Brook, then transferred back to Columbia for the rest of my Ph.D., because my then-girlfriend, now-wife, was continuing on from Columbia undergrad to grad school.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alison on Jumping Monkeys!</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2008-03-16-alison-on-jumping-monkeys/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2008 17:30:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2008-03-16-alison-on-jumping-monkeys/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alison was interviewed on one of our favorite podcasts, Jumping Monkeys. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jumpingmonkeys.com/jumpingmonkeys/2008/03/jumping-monke-2.html&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the episode page&lt;/a&gt;. She discusses home archives and how to approach saving your family&amp;rsquo;s stuff for the future. Cool!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Competitiveness considered harmful?</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2007-12-13-competitiveness-considered-harmful/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2007 16:53:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2007-12-13-competitiveness-considered-harmful/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over Thanksgiving, I was complaining about people who crowd forward when boarding a plane, even if their row hasn&amp;rsquo;t been called, so that when it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; called, they get on first. And if they can get away with boarding before their row is called, they&amp;rsquo;ll do that too. Someone close to me retorted, &amp;ldquo;competition made the human race what it is today.&amp;rdquo; I haven&amp;rsquo;t stopped thinking about that remark ever since. Can this person be right? I dearly, dearly hope not. Because all I can think of in reply is, &amp;ldquo;yes, it did make us what we are &amp;ndash; especially the World Wars and the Holocaust.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lord of the Rings soundtrack</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2007-11-30-lord-of-the-rings-soundtrack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2007 20:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2007-11-30-lord-of-the-rings-soundtrack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m listening to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Lord-Rings-Return-Complete-Recordings/dp/B000V6BE6M/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;s=music&amp;qid=1196454269&amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Return of the King: The Complete Recordings&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; at work, and I&amp;rsquo;m at the point near the (first) end when Frodo and Sam have just destroyed the ring (with Gollum&amp;rsquo;s unwitting help) and they&amp;rsquo;re escaping the flowing lava by standing on a rock, feeling a relieved. With all the events of the story to back up the scene, I think it&amp;rsquo;s truly moving to see these two regular guys, who together destroyed a great and senseless evil power. I actually see it as a very tragic moment, when two of the world&amp;rsquo;s great forces are being presented to us via the heightened drama of this point in the story: senseless evil/destruction/chaos on the one hand, and the fortitude and perseverance and good of the common person on the other hand. You can ask all sorts of questions at this point, like if the common person is so good, where is all the evil coming from? Why must the most ordinary and good people sustain such injury and sacrifice to ward off the worst effects of the evil?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Masterpiece Theater?</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2007-11-19-masterpiece-theater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2007 22:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2007-11-19-masterpiece-theater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Has &lt;em&gt;Masterpiece Theater&lt;/em&gt; always just been some British TV show? Lately they&amp;rsquo;ve been showing &lt;em&gt;The Amazing Mrs. Prithcard&lt;/em&gt;, which felt like an American TV show that happened to be British. Is it a masterpiece? Did they pick it because they felt it was a masterpiece? Maybe they should rename Masterpiece Theater to &amp;ldquo;Some British TV Show&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lord of the Rings, movie versus book</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2007-09-27-lord-of-the-rings-movie-versus-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2007 22:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2007-09-27-lord-of-the-rings-movie-versus-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A while back I wanted to read &lt;em&gt;The Lord of the Rings&lt;/em&gt; aloud with my wife. We&amp;rsquo;ve read lots of books together this way, and I&amp;rsquo;m a huge LOTR fan, so I really wanted to share it. The problem is it&amp;rsquo;s very long and many people consider lots of it boring. So, I took a clever (if I do say so myself) shortcut! I went through the books and dog-eared ranges of pages where the plot differed from the movies in a way I thought significant or noteworthy. For example, I read the entire chapter &amp;ldquo;The scouring of the shire&amp;rdquo; because this was left out of the movie. I highlighted the differences in Denethor&amp;rsquo;s character as much as I could, as well as Faramir&amp;rsquo;s. Both were substantially diminished in moral quality in the movies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Jasons</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2006-08-10-the-jasons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2006 01:09:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2006-08-10-the-jasons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently heard of a book called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0670034894/ref=nosim/002-6749880-5641633?n=283155&#34;&gt;The Jasons&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.math.columbia.edu/~woit/wordpress/?p=376&#34;&gt;the blog of a former colleague&lt;/a&gt;, Peter Woit. Since I spent the summer of 2004 doing classified math research for the government, I was very interested to hear of another such group. In a way, the Jasons are a sequel to the very successful Manhattan Project, and there is lots of overlap of personnel. The Jasons came into being in the aftermath of the Soviet launch of Sputnik, in 1960 to be exact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The huamn mnid</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2006-07-26-the-huamn-mnid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2006 02:57:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2006-07-26-the-huamn-mnid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Aoccdrnig to a rscheearch at Cmabrigde Uinervtisy, it deosn&amp;rsquo;t mttaer in waht oredr the ltteers in a wrod are, the olny iprmoetnt tihng is taht the frist and lsat ltteer be at the rghit pclae. The rset can be a toatl mses and you can sitll raed it wouthit porbelm. Tihs is bcuseae the huamn mnid deos not raed ervey lteter by istlef, but the wrod as a wlohe.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intelligent Design: The Final Word, Part 3</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2006-03-12-intelligent-design-the-final-word-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2006 21:53:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2006-03-12-intelligent-design-the-final-word-part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The central question I have been trying to satisfy myself about with these notes is the following: is there a way to formulate Intelligent Design as a scientific theory? (See &lt;a href=&#34;http://greg.langmead.info/?p=61&#34;&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://greg.langmead.info/?p=62&#34;&gt;part 2&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intelligent Design: The Final Word, Part 2</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2006-03-12-intelligent-design-the-final-word-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2006 21:32:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2006-03-12-intelligent-design-the-final-word-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a continuation of my discussion of ID (see &lt;a href=&#34;http://greg.langmead.info/?p=61&#34;&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt;). Here in part 2 I have exerpted from Behe&amp;rsquo;s book in order to summarize his argument. I am using the 2003 trade paperback edition published by Free Press, lent to me by a work colleague.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intelligent Design: The Final Word, Part 1</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2006-03-12-intelligent-design-the-final-word-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2006 20:59:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2006-03-12-intelligent-design-the-final-word-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am finally ready to write some definitive thoughts about Intelligent Design. I just finished reading Michael Behe&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;em&gt;Darwin&amp;rsquo;s Black Box&lt;/em&gt; from 1996, and I&amp;rsquo;ve thought about it from the perspective of science, falsifiability, religion, and philosophy. I would like to be very careful about where I plan and do not plan to take issue with him, so let me start in Part 1 by delineating the argument.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Written verbal tics</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2005-12-10-written-verbal-tics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2005 22:17:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2005-12-10-written-verbal-tics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to write this down for a long time. There are two very widespread and very annoying idioms that I see a lot in amateur writing. The main example of the kind of writing I mean is product reviews on sites like Amazon, but I see it also on Macworld, CNet and other more professional sites.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2005-10-19-contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2005 04:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2005-10-19-contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just watched &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0790733226/104-8979811-4830322?v=glance&amp;n=130&amp;n=507846&amp;s=dvd&amp;v=glance&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; again for the first time in a while. A major theme of the movie is that the goals of science and religion are so hard to untangle that the two main protagonists have a very complicated adult relationship based on it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Irrational Design?</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2005-10-09-irrational-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2005 22:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2005-10-09-irrational-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a great deal of controversy at the moment over Intelligent Design (ID) being taught in science classrooms. I have always felt very strongly about the dangers faced by science in our society, and this crisis is a perfect example of what can happen without careful vigilance on the part of science teachers and practitioners.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poker</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2005-04-26-poker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2005 01:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2005-04-26-poker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had poker on my mind since last Thanksgiving, specifically Texas Hold&amp;rsquo;em. At this point, I have special hold&amp;rsquo;em software, four poker strategy books and one nonfiction book about poker. I mostly study the books and play a bit with the software, but eventually I want to start a real-money account on one of the online poker sites. I feel that if I apply what&amp;rsquo;s in the books, then I can win money, which would be a very fun goal to shoot for. Of course, to avoid having a gambling problem I have to tread very carefully and lower my expectations within reason for the early stages. I have been procrastinating setting up a new checking account for my poker money both because I truly hesitate to take this step, and because I don&amp;rsquo;t feel I&amp;rsquo;m good enough yet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daylight Savings Time</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2005-04-08-daylight-savings-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2005 05:16:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2005-04-08-daylight-savings-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t understand daylight savings time. No one I talk to has a clear idea of when and why it was invented. What country started it?  What countries adhere to it?  Why is Europe still doing it a week before the US?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C. S. Lewis 2005</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2005-01-17-c-s-lewis-2005/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2005 01:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2005-01-17-c-s-lewis-2005/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I visited my parents for the holidays again this year, and like last year I decided to read some of their C. S. Lewis collection. I felt like progressing on with his Christian works, and so I chose &lt;em&gt;Mere Christianity&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Civil War</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2004-07-17-the-civil-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2004 16:07:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2004-07-17-the-civil-war/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been renting Ken Burns&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;Civil War&lt;/em&gt; shows lately, from Netflix. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share a misconception I learned I had about the Civil War. My memory from school left me thinking that the war would involve a large set of complicated virtuosic battlefield maneuvers, and that I&amp;rsquo;d come to appreciate how all the famous generals were geniuses. In fact, I&amp;rsquo;d somehow developed the opinion that the generals during that war outshine generals in other wars, that through a coincidence of history, the best strategists somehow simultaneously appeared during that conflict.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does Tolkien think Good always defeats Evil?</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2004-06-01-does-tolkien-think-good-always-defeats-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2004 02:54:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2004-06-01-does-tolkien-think-good-always-defeats-evil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always thought Tolkien was essentially pessimistic, despite the happy ending of &lt;em&gt;The Lord of the Rings&lt;/em&gt;. The power of Evil he describes, and the inevibatle comparisons to the horror of World War I make this a convincing point of view. The army of Gondor is forced to risk a suicidal attack against a formidable foe to even preserve their tiny ghost of a chance of victory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New feature: better links</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2004-04-17-new-feature-better-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2004 21:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2004-04-17-new-feature-better-links/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new feature on Long Head is the new super-accurate &amp;ldquo;Greg Links&amp;rdquo; list on the left. Except for the other langmead.info sites, these links are the sites I&amp;rsquo;m actually actively reading every day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book review: C. S. Lewis</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2004-04-17-book-review-c-s-lewis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2004 21:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2004-04-17-book-review-c-s-lewis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This winter I read three books by C. S. Lewis: &lt;em&gt;The Great Divorce&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Screwtape Letters&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Surprised by Joy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been introduced to Lewis before, when I was young. I read the first several books of the &lt;em&gt;Narnia&lt;/em&gt; series, and I read the whole &lt;em&gt;Out of the Silent Planet&lt;/em&gt; trilogy. Back then, however, I was looking for pure entertainment from those books, and although they delivered it, the religious level was also apparent, and detracted from their enjoyment for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MathType for Mac&#39;s out!</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2004-03-26-mathtype-for-macs-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2004 19:25:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2004-03-26-mathtype-for-macs-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After nearly three years of development, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dessci.com/en/products/mathtype/mtm_upgrade.htm&#34;&gt;MathType 5 for Mac&lt;/a&gt; has been released.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a long time coming, and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to moving on to other projects, but for now I&amp;rsquo;m happy it&amp;rsquo;s finished.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coming soon...</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2004-02-12-coming-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2004 05:32:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2004-02-12-coming-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be adding my thoughts soon about three books by C. S. Lewis that I&amp;rsquo;ve recently finished. Although I had a few false starts with the Narnia books as a youth, these were read more to find out about the real Christian thinker, and because I wanted to branch out from Tolkien to some of his colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m a pundit, I&#39;m punditing, I pun</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-12-04-im-a-pundit-im-punditing-i-pun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2003 04:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-12-04-im-a-pundit-im-punditing-i-pun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I decided to put some thought into why I have so much trouble getting good at real-time strategy computer games. I went ahead and submitted it to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gamespot.com&#34;&gt;GameSpot&lt;/a&gt;, my favorite gaming news site, which does a weekly set of op-ed pieces with a slot for a reader to opine. Well, my article was accepted! &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gamespot.com/features/6084762/index.html&#34;&gt;Have a read&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;m the second one down.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blogging from bed</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-06-28-blogging-from-bed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2003 07:58:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-06-28-blogging-from-bed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Got wireless today! It&amp;rsquo;s totally new to me, but not to most other people, so I won&amp;rsquo;t dwell on it. Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;m in bed, which means Penelope is in the chair and Alison&amp;rsquo;s got her arms all over my pillows. This laptop has a very loud hard drive, which I already knew, but which is a bit more of a problem in this context.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Want to Miss a Thing</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-06-11-dont-want-to-miss-a-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2003 05:59:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-06-11-dont-want-to-miss-a-thing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just finished watching &lt;em&gt;Armageddon&lt;/em&gt; and it reminds me of an issue I have with the grammar of the Aerosmith/Dianne Warren song &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t Want to Miss a Thing.&amp;rdquo; The lyrics go &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;don&amp;rsquo;t want to fall asleep / &amp;lsquo;cause I miss you babe / and I don&amp;rsquo;t want to miss a thing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m 30</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-04-20-im-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2003 17:53:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-04-20-im-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Bunny Cake!&#34; src=&#34;https://greg.langmead.info/img/BunnyCake.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was my 30th birthday. Alison threw me a surprise party (just the two of us) on Friday night and made me a bunny cake! Yesterday she gave me a bottle of &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; nice tequila, and I had some with breakfast ;-). My brother got me a book, and there are more gifts on the way that I don&amp;rsquo;t know what they are. Alison and I had a nice visit to our favorite boba tea place in Long Beach, then headed over to Anaheim to see the Angels play the Mariners, and I got a proper Angels hat. It&amp;rsquo;s made of really light, breathable material and it was very comfortable. It also represents some sort of turning point for me, as I do not change baseball allegience lightly, though eventually I guess I always do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alison&#39;s PhD</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-04-14-alisons-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2003 04:39:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-04-14-alisons-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This past week, my wife&amp;rsquo;s dissertation was aproved by Columbia&amp;rsquo;s dissertation office, meaning the printouts had the right margins, her paperwork made its way from the Art History department, her library fees were all paid, her account was in good standing, and 12 years of your typical bureaucratic wrangling has sorted itself out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buy me toys!</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-04-08-buy-me-toys/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2003 04:14:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-04-08-buy-me-toys/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My birthday&amp;rsquo;s coming up, so head on over to amazon.com and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/registry/1T63DINEDI1C1/ref%3Dwl%5Fs%5F3/104-1790558-0272731&#34;&gt;check out my wish list&lt;/a&gt;! :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So I guess I&#39;ve made</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-03-08-so-i-guess-ive-made/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2003 18:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-03-08-so-i-guess-ive-made/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I guess I&amp;rsquo;ve made a mess of all my various weblogs. First there was a Movable Type blog in 2001, then a radio blog, then a new radio blog, and then this new Movable Type blog. I&amp;rsquo;m going to settle on this one, but all my old posts to the other blogs will just have to be lost unless I can muster the enthusiasm for scrounging them up somehow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Still working on Fabric of</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-03-08-still-working-on-fabric-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2003 18:35:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-03-08-still-working-on-fabric-of/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Still working on &lt;em&gt;Fabric of Reality&lt;/em&gt;, because I am a little lost in the chapter on quantum computing, which was the main topic I bought the book to read about. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll figure it out eventually.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Now that I&#39;m finished American</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-03-08-now-that-im-finished-american/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2003 18:34:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-03-08-now-that-im-finished-american/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that I&amp;rsquo;m finished &lt;em&gt;American Gods&lt;/em&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;m just reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/014027541X/qid=1046661995/sr=12-1/104-0484812-0662315?v=glance&amp;s=books&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Fabric of Reality&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by David Deutsch. It&amp;rsquo;s about physics, quantum computation, DNA, and lots of other topics, sort of unified into a really interesting and idiosyncratic world-view. David Deutsch is a father of quantum computing, so he knows what he&amp;rsquo;s talking about. I always prefer well-expressed personal viewpoints to bland, objective information.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I just finished reading American</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-03-08-i-just-finished-reading-american/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2003 18:33:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-03-08-i-just-finished-reading-american/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just finished reading &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0380789035/qid=1046661792/sr=12-1/104-0484812-0662315?v=glance&amp;s=books&#34;&gt;American Gods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; by Neil Gaiman. I enjoyed it, but it was a little slow. Basically it explores the idea (in fictional form) that gods from the various pantheons traveled to America with the settlers and started trying to eke their living here. In this day and age, it&amp;rsquo;s not easy to be a god, and they&amp;rsquo;re almost like pathetic people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oh my, I haven&#39;t posted</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-03-08-oh-my-i-havent-posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2003 18:32:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-03-08-oh-my-i-havent-posted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oh my, I haven&amp;rsquo;t posted for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long Head moving to Langmead.info</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-08-14-long-head-moving-to-langmeadinfo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2002 07:51:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-08-14-long-head-moving-to-langmeadinfo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Test, test. Blah, blah, blah.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We have proper internet hosting</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-08-01-we-have-proper-internet-hosting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2002 21:34:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-08-01-we-have-proper-internet-hosting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have proper internet hosting now, via the domain langmead.info. More soon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alison and I are all</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-05-17-alison-and-i-are-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2002 02:33:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-05-17-alison-and-i-are-all/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alison and I are all set up in L.A.! We have an apartment on the beach, and two cars. We&amp;rsquo;re moving June 1. &lt;a href=&#34;http://homepage.mac.com/langmead/PhotoAlbum5.html&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; are some pictures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So I have progressed nicely</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-05-07-so-i-have-progressed-nicely/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2002 02:32:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-05-07-so-i-have-progressed-nicely/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I have progressed nicely in my quest to hear new music that I like. I bought two CDs! Blur&amp;rsquo;s greatest hits (or is it &amp;ldquo;best of?&amp;rdquo;) and Ben Folds Five (Whatever and ever amen).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I need new music. For</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-03-26-i-need-new-music-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2002 02:09:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-03-26-i-need-new-music-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I need new music. For years I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to a core group of bands: XTC, Beatles, Squeeze, Joe Jackson, various solo Beatles, R.E.M., Billy Joel and They Might Be Giants, with smaller amounts of the B-52&amp;rsquo;s, Indigo Girls, and a little Classical (mostly Mozart, Bach and Beethoven of course).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I recently rented The Lord</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-03-14-i-recently-rented-the-lord/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2002 02:07:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-03-14-i-recently-rented-the-lord/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently rented &lt;em&gt;The Lord of the Rings&lt;/em&gt; in audiobook format, on CD, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.recordedbooks.com&#34;&gt;Recorded Books&lt;/a&gt;. They make, sell, and rent audiobooks. When you rent, they send you the books in a box-within-a-box. The inner box is for sending it back, so there is very little hassle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I was thinking about Close</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-03-02-i-was-thinking-about-close/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2002 21:33:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-03-02-i-was-thinking-about-close/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was thinking about &lt;em&gt;Close Encounters of the Third Kind&lt;/em&gt; the other day. I was pretty young, so take this with a grain of salt, but here&amp;rsquo;s what I was thinking. At the beginning, a mood of chaos is set when as-yet-unintroduced high-ranking officials meet in a remote location where a World War II plane (boat?) has been found.  They arrive in a helicopter, and part of the fun and tension of the scene is the landing of this loud helicopter. It really is exciting, because, you know, you don&amp;rsquo;t see helicopters land every day.  These guys must really be important, and there must be quite a bit of urgency!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There is a lot of</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-02-28-there-is-a-lot-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2002 21:32:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-02-28-there-is-a-lot-of/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of buzz about a book called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gonzomarkets.com/cluetrain&#34;&gt;The Cluetrain Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;. I can&amp;rsquo;t tell if it&amp;rsquo;s about dotcoms, or about social forces in the Internet Age. But, they provided the whole book online, so I ciphoned it onto my Palm and I&amp;rsquo;m going to read it. I&amp;rsquo;ll keep you posted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speaking of books, here is</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-02-28-speaking-of-books-here-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2002 21:26:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-02-28-speaking-of-books-here-is/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Speaking of books, here is my reading list for the coming months:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0451524934/qid=1014952968/sr=8-1/ref=sr_8_67_1/102-2574653-3061724&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;1984&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, by George Orwell&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oreilly.com/~stevet/fdnc/index.html&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Future Does Not Compute: Overcoming the Machines in our Midst&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, by Steve Talbott. (See also &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oreilly.com/~stevet/netfuture/faq.html&#34;&gt;the FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for his excellent ongoing email newsletter &amp;ldquo;Netfuture.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0312863551/qid=1014953271/sr=1-1/ref=sr_1_1/102-2574653-3061724&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Moon is a Harsh Mistress&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, by Robert Heinlein&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0195106466/qid=1014953344/sr=1-2/ref=sr_1_2/102-2574653-3061724&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shadows of the Mind: A Search for the Missing Science of Consciousness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, by Roger Penrose&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0553575384/qid=1014953389/sr=1-1/ref=sr_1_1/102-2574653-3061724&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;To Say Nothing of the Dog&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, by Connie Willis&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alison came up with an</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-02-28-alison-came-up-with-an/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2002 21:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-02-28-alison-came-up-with-an/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alison came up with an interesting quote in her dissertation research on 12th century France:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I hear more and more about this time period from Alison, I see why she studies history. It sheds light forward onto our own time. Would you describe our current ways of thinking as &amp;ldquo;eschewing univocal interpretations,&amp;rdquo; because I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t. I forget who said the following but I agree and I guess so would the scholars of 1100: the older I get, the more I learn that not only is it okay to hold contradictory beliefs, but the deepest, most important elements of life are bound up in such opposing truths.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jingo Bells, Jingo Bells...</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-02-09-jingo-bells-jingo-bells/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2002 01:34:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-02-09-jingo-bells-jingo-bells/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was really looking forward to the opening ceremonies of the Winter Olympics tonight, but over the last few days I&amp;rsquo;ve been growing increasingly uneasy about what I might see there. As it turned out, after the initial voice-overs by Messrs. McKay (co-alum of my high school!) and Costas, I turned off the television. I&amp;rsquo;m only going to tune in when events I want to see are on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aging</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/1999-01-29-aging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 1999 04:11:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/1999-01-29-aging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;1998Banner&#34; src=&#34;http://greg.langmead.info/wp-content/uploads/2008/03/banner.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note, this was written before I had a blog. I recovered it from the Internet Archive. Back in graduate school I had a “musings” section of my site and those essays are in the same spirit as this blog so I’ve added them with retroactive datestamps.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Titanic</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/1998-04-17-titanic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 1998 17:43:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/1998-04-17-titanic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;1998Banner&#34; src=&#34;http://greg.langmead.info/wp-content/uploads/2008/03/banner.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note, this was written before I had a blog. I recovered it from the Internet Archive. Back in graduate school I had a &amp;ldquo;musings&amp;rdquo; section of my site and those essays are in the same spirit as this blog so I&amp;rsquo;ve added them with retroactive datestamps.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
