<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tech | Long Head</title>
    <link>https://greg.langmead.info/category/tech/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://greg.langmead.info/category/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Tech</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2009 15:04:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://greg.langmead.info/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Tech</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/category/tech/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPhone hack: reading strap</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2009-11-30-iphone-hack-reading-strap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2009 15:04:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2009-11-30-iphone-hack-reading-strap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I use my iPhone quite heavily as an ebook reader. I read in various situations, but one of the most frequent is when I&amp;rsquo;m in bed. When you&amp;rsquo;re lying down, either on your back or on your side, it can be quite a strain on your hand muscles to grip the phone and also use your thumb to scroll the pages. So a while back, I came up with a super-cheap way to improve the situation by adding a strap that holds the phone to your hand (actually, it holds it to just your index finger). Whenever I show this trick to other folks, including seasoned, cynical tech folks, they seem impressed. So I thought I would post it for search engines to find. All you need are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  * an iPhone or iPod touch, any model
  * a case that covers just the back of your phone
  * a thick rubber band (you might need to try a few sizes to get one that&#39;s comfy)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried other kinds of straps besides a rubber band, but the elasticity and rubber material both make it very comfortable and easy to grip your hand. You might need to try a few different sizes of rubber band, to get the tightness and thickness that are most comfortable for you. Lay all these items out like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://greg.langmead.info/wp-content/uploads/2009/11/IMG_1201.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;ingredients&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice my Incipio case is looking cracked and old, after just a year! I do not recommend that brand. I think the dust inside is from all the rubber bands I&amp;rsquo;ve used :). Anyway, next you wrap the rubber band around the case. I find that if you do it at an angle, it is more comfortable for your hand and provides more alternatives for finger positions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://greg.langmead.info/wp-content/uploads/2009/11/IMG_1203.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;rubber band around case&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, put the iphone in the case, on top of the rubber band. You may have to work some slack into the rubber band, so that the phone can nestle into the case without straining against the rubber band. The phone won&amp;rsquo;t fit all the way into the case since the rubber band has some thickness, but I don&amp;rsquo;t really notice it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://greg.langmead.info/wp-content/uploads/2009/11/IMG_1204.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;iPhone, rubber band, and case&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here it is from the back:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://greg.langmead.info/wp-content/uploads/2009/11/IMG_1205.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;rear view&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, whenever you want to hold the phone for extended periods, just slip your index finger through the rubber band.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://greg.langmead.info/wp-content/uploads/2009/11/IMG_1206.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;finger in rubber band&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your hand muscles can relax, and you can much more easily use your thumb to scroll the pages of an ebook:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://greg.langmead.info/wp-content/uploads/2009/11/IMG_1207.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;scrolling ebook&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure a case manufacturer could do much better with a built-in strap, but so far I have yet to see a case like that. In the meantime, enjoy this trick and enjoy reading ebooks!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infocom games, using your voice</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2008-08-17-infocom-games-using-your-voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2008 05:17:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2008-08-17-infocom-games-using-your-voice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a long history with Infocom games (&amp;ldquo;text adventures&amp;rdquo; was what I called them as a kid, and &amp;ldquo;interactive fiction&amp;rdquo; is the new name). People still write these games, did you know that? There&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://ifdb.tads.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;big archive&lt;/a&gt; and an &lt;a href=&#34;http://ifcomp.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;annual competition&lt;/a&gt;. I haven&amp;rsquo;t played any of the non-Infocom variety, though I think I ought to try one. I have copies of all the data files for all the original Infocom games from the 80s, and for years there has been an open-source program to load these files and let you play the games. It&amp;rsquo;s called &lt;a href=&#34;http://frotz.sourceforge.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Frotz&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a version of Frotz on all my computers for the last 12 years, including my various Palm PDAs. The only Infocom game I&amp;rsquo;ve ever finished in my life (making it one of like 5 games of any variety that I have ever finished) was &amp;ldquo;Enchanter&amp;rdquo;, which I played on the Palm. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://phobos.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=287653015&amp;amp;mt=8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;latest incarnation of Frotz&lt;/a&gt; is for the iPhone, and so of course I downloaded it right away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PDAs in general are not the easiest devices to type on, though, and there&amp;rsquo;s lots of typing in Infocom games. So it occurred to me that it would be really cool to speak the commands. After all, there is a limited vocabulary, which should be ideal for getting good accuracy from automatic speech recognition, and furthermore the engine should require a pretty small amount of data. On top of that, what if Frotz synthesized a (pleasant, configurable) computer voice to read you all the text in the game? Then you could set the iPhone down in front of you, close your eyes, and enjoy a nice bit of interactive fiction by having a dialog with thin air. All of a sudden the very stodgiest and oldest of technology leapfrogs three decades of competition and actually sounds futuristic! I patted myself on the back for thinking of such a great idea, and told myself I&amp;rsquo;d take a stab at it myself &amp;ldquo;one day,&amp;rdquo; since speech recognition is just a hop, skip and a jump away from machine translation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that&amp;rsquo;s not all, there&amp;rsquo;s a punchline to this story. It further occurred to me that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been the first to think of this idea, so I did a Google search. &lt;a href=&#34;http://iphonefrotz.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/doc/SPEECH&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The link I found&lt;/a&gt; is inside a code repository for Frotz itself, namely the iPhone version. Actually, this is just a branch of Frotz, so I checked the general Frotz SourceForge repository as well and the same file is there too. It&amp;rsquo;s a placeholder for future work on just this idea, but it&amp;rsquo;s super-vague and kind of creepy, what with the whole &amp;ldquo;commissioned by a presently undisclosed party&amp;rdquo; thing. The technology looks good, it&amp;rsquo;s all open-source stuff released by academics, which was where I figured I would start looking as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So who wrote this document, and when, and when do they intend to come out of the shadows with the result of their work? Who knows &amp;ndash; but it sure is a weird end to my story.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft engineers couldn&#39;t care less</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2008-06-20-microsoft-engineers-couldnt-care-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2008 18:48:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2008-06-20-microsoft-engineers-couldnt-care-less/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Excel was released in 1985 for the Mac and in 1987 for Windows. Today I was using the 2007 version. After 20 years of work by countless engineers, it cannot open two files with the same name, and the dialog is quite shameless about it. That&amp;rsquo;s a good word: &amp;ldquo;shameless.&amp;rdquo; Details are everything. Click to see the full size.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://greg.langmead.info/wp-content/uploads/2008/06/excel_cant_open_samename.png&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://greg.langmead.info/wp-content/uploads/2008/06/excel_cant_open_samename.png&#34; alt=&#34;excel_cant_open_samename.png&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I won my fight with Windows Media Player</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2008-05-18-i-won-my-fight-with-windows-media-player/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2008 04:18:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2008-05-18-i-won-my-fight-with-windows-media-player/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you know, I want to stream movies and music from my PC to my TV. I have an all-star lineup of tools:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  * PC running Vista with Windows Media Player 11 (WMP11), iTunes, and Zune software
  * Xbox 360
  * PlayStation 3
  * TiVo
  * Airport Express
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And a selection of Xvid, Divx, MPEG 4, MP3, and AAC files to stream. These are all extremely widely used formats, the most popular in their categories (the first three are video, the last two are audio). All the players I mentioned play these formats, at least after installing some popular codec packs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PlayStation 3 has the best and most responsive remote,  the best music visualizations (cool effects that show on TV while you&amp;rsquo;re listening to music), and the nicest UI. And it natively supports all the formats I listed. So all I have to do is get stuff to stream to it! BUT&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  * Zune will only stream to Xbox 360
  * iTunes will only stream to the Airport Express, which is audio only
  * WMP11 will not add MPEG 4 or AAC files to its library or stream them
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today I targeted the MPEG 4 portion of this last point using &lt;a href=&#34;http://a8t8.spaces.live.com/blog/cns!2518DD508BB713E8!156.entry?commentPage=Last&amp;amp;commentPH=&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;these instructions&lt;/a&gt;. It took lots of Googling and experimentation before I finally found those instructions, but it was worth it. I closed the loop, so that I can stream the things that &amp;ldquo;should&amp;rdquo; work to the device that &amp;ldquo;should&amp;rdquo; play them! Yay!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How old is the term &#39;bug&#39;?</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2008-03-16-how-old-is-the-term-bug/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2008 17:29:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2008-03-16-how-old-is-the-term-bug/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Robert X. Cringely, my favorite tech pundit, had an interesting aside in this week&amp;rsquo;s column (which is otherwise about Apple and Blu-Ray). He ran across a use of the term &amp;lsquo;bug&amp;rsquo; to mean a glitch in a technical system in a magazine article from the 1930s. I found this fascinating, since we always assume &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo; invented the term when computers came along. He closes with this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;It turns out that &#34;bug&#34; was a common term for hardware glitches and dates back to the 19th century and possibly before. Edison used the term in a letter he wrote in 1878. This is no earthshaking news, of course, but simply reminds me how self-centered we are as an industry and there really isn&#39;t much that&#39;s truly new.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pbs.org/cringely/pulpit/2008/pulpit_20080314_004511.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Read the full article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More on Zune (Moron Zune?)</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2007-11-14-more-on-zune-moron-zune/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2007 17:21:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2007-11-14-more-on-zune-moron-zune/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Zune software turned out not to be so great at working with iTunes playlists. It&amp;rsquo;s not a dynamic synchronization, just a one-time thing. So after asking the Zune to read my iTunes playlists, it did so, but after I changed my playlists in iTunes, the Zune did not see the change. Also, the Zune does not attempt to pull in the smart playlists, just the static ones. Even just treating the smart playlists as regular ones and pulling in their current contents would have been great, but no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My last gripe is that there are playlists I can&amp;rsquo;t get rid of with the attractive names &amp;ldquo;__127.0.0.1&amp;rdquo; and similar. Why is the software showing me its disgusting internal details?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The possibly good news is that Microsoft have just done a major overhaul to the Zune software, and so some of these problems may be gone. On the other hand, they may be replaced with more ridiculous problems!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two reasons to download Microsoft&#39;s Zune software</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2007-10-08-two-reasons-to-download-microsofts-zune-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2007 18:05:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2007-10-08-two-reasons-to-download-microsofts-zune-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft includes a Windows-based desktop media player with their Zune portable media players, to manage your music and sync it with the Zune. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot like Windows Media Player, which I despise, but actually if you own an Xbox 360 there are two reasons to install the Zune software even if you don&amp;rsquo;t own a Zune:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It can serve MPEG4 and H.264 movies to the Xbox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It can synchronize its music library and playlists with iTunes automatically, and serve those to the Xbox as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;H.264 is a popular media format supported by many devices: iPod, Zune, PlayStation Portable, Xbox 360, PlayStation 3, and Tivo. Files in this format are sold by the Xbox movie store and the iTunes store. It is also one of the underlying formats supported on both Blu-Ray and HD-DVD formats. So it&amp;rsquo;s important to be able to get all your videos in that format, and when you do, you want to play them on your Xbox 360 in HD, right? Right! Well, the Zune software is the easiest way to do that. It has the same media sharing features (and dialog boxes) as Windows Media Player, it just supports more formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for syncing with iTunes, I just discovered this over the weekend. It does not support playing DRM music purchased at the iTunes store, but as DRM starts to disappear, this will matter less over time. I activated the feature (here are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.internet-nexus.com/2007/09/sync-itunes-windows-media-player-and.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; the instructions I used&lt;/a&gt;), and after a long time all my iTunes &lt;em&gt;regular&lt;/em&gt; playlists did in fact appear in Zune and on my Xbox 360 as well (under the Music item of course). But none of my iTunes &lt;em&gt;smart&lt;/em&gt; playlists made it over, which is a shame because I use them rather heavily. I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll have to make static playlist copies of the ones I care about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet discovered how often it syncs up with iTunes, but I&amp;rsquo;ll find out once I make those static playlists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download the Zune software &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zune.net/en-us/meetzune/software.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;from Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Struggles with new computer</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2007-09-27-struggles-with-new-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2007 23:29:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2007-09-27-struggles-with-new-computer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I bought all the bits and pieces to build a new PC for home. My old one is a few years old now, and isn&amp;rsquo;t up for all the video transcoding I throw at it these days (mainly converting Xvid and Divx TV shows into MP4 for use on Xbox). I&amp;rsquo;m not a real hardware guru, but every few years I read enough to know what the state of the art is and roll up my sleeves for a few weeks. This time I had one small snafu which was that nothing powered on after I put it together. It turned out that the problem was the CPU was not completely seated. I had to twist it off of its heatsink, straighten a bent pin, and re-seat it. Wow, it worked!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far I&amp;rsquo;ve installed Vista, and a few basic apps. Next I need to move all my hard drives over, but since for some reason I installed my biggest drive as Raid 0 (with just itself in the array), I have to move the files off and reformat it on the new system. To help with that, I purchased an external USB hard drive that will also help me store completed iMovie projects so that I an keep one Greer movie at a time on my Powerbook.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon music downloads</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2007-09-27-amazon-music-downloads/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2007 23:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2007-09-27-amazon-music-downloads/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ars Technica is a wonderful tech news site that&amp;rsquo;s fast becoming more and more like a &lt;strong&gt;real&lt;/strong&gt; news source, with journalists and investigation and everything!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, recently &lt;a href=&#34;http://arstechnica.com/news.ars/post/20070925-amazon-launches-public-beta-of-mp3-music-store.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;they reviewed&lt;/a&gt; Amazon&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/browse/-/163856011&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;new MP3 store&lt;/a&gt;. It sounded very positive because they sell straight MP3 files with no rights management, and so the files will play on my iPod.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yesterday I went to the store and browsed. The top 100 albums are all on sale for $8.99, and I saw a new They Might Be Giants album in the list that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about, so I bought it. It was a great experience. You first download a little downloader app that fetches all the songs and adds them directly to the iTunes library. Because they&amp;rsquo;re MP3, they will be playable on Tivo, Xbox, or any other home media device. We&amp;rsquo;re growing increasingly dependent on these sorts of devices around the house, so this is important. Plus the 256kbps encoding is of a very high quality, the highest of any store (tied with Apple&amp;rsquo;s own DRM-free music). And the prices is cheaper than iTunes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One moral is that the iTunes-iPod ecosystem is not so &amp;ldquo;sticky&amp;rdquo; for me. I left the iTunes music store to use Amazon with no internal debate at all. Now whenever I want new music, I&amp;rsquo;ll check Amazon first, then fall back to iTunes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, one disadvantage of Amazon: they only have 2 million songs compared to iTunes&amp;rsquo; 6 million. But surely that&amp;rsquo;s temporary and soon all the stores will have all the same stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One view on the state of media-in-the-home</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2007-02-04-one-view-on-the-state-of-media-in-the-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2007 18:14:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2007-02-04-one-view-on-the-state-of-media-in-the-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Within the last year, I&amp;rsquo;ve purchased both an Xbox 360 and an HDTV (a 37&amp;quot; Sharp Aquos LCD). I have a TiVo, a home network, a Powerbook, and a fast PC with lots of storage. Surely somewhere in all of that is a viable, clean, easy to use method of expanding what I can enjoy on my home entertainment center to include my iTunes music, any downloaded video files, saved TiVo videos, and personal photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The executive summary is that I&amp;rsquo;m going to be purchasing a Mac Mini when they are next updated by Apple (should be soon), because that is going to be the most flexible entertainment hub. I also learned that our household is more of an Apple shop than I had guessed, mainly due to iTunes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have tried several scenarios, mostly focused on viewing downloaded TV shows on my TV:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Streaming videos from Windows XP to the Xbox with on-the-fly re-encoding (explained below)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Streaming videos from Windows XP to the Xbox with manually re-encoded files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Streaming videos from Windows Vista Media Center to the Xbox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Playing videos on TiVo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using my PowerBook plugged directly into the TV to play movies using Front Row&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Xbox 360 is designed to talk to any Windows XP machine using Media Player 11, or to Windows Media Center. You use different areas of the Xbox menus to access either of these two, and they have some differences and similarities. If you are connecting to plain Media Player, say for Videos, then you access a &amp;ldquo;Videos&amp;rdquo; item on the Xbox and it connects to the PC and shows a flat list of videos. Here are a few reasons that this seemingly futuristic capability completely sucks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Xbox can only play movies in WMV format, which is very rarely used anywhere. This means that almost any video you already have, and any TV show you download from the internet, is in the wrong format to play on the Xbox. But let&amp;rsquo;s pretend for a minute that you&amp;rsquo;ve converted everything to this format, as there are other things that suck.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The video listing you get is a flat list with no playlists or other organizing schemes, and only the filename is shown, with no way to give it a piece of metadata like a title. This just does not scale to even 3 seasons of TV shows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you play a video, you cannot resume playback to a previously-viewed point. You have to fastforward to where you were. This is a typical Microsoft UI oversight, and we ran into this issue approximately EVERY DAY.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To populate this list in the first place, you must share your Windows Media Player 11 library using &amp;ldquo;media sharing&amp;rdquo;. This seemed cool at first, since I thought that like iTunes, your library would be shared, since that&amp;rsquo;s what the name says. Nope. None of your playlists are shared &lt;em&gt;for videos&lt;/em&gt;, only your audio playlists. Instead, only the videos that live inside so-called &amp;ldquo;Watched Folders&amp;rdquo; are shared. This means you have to get Media Player to monitor a folder and have it always add any new files to your library. To me, the purpose of a media library is so that I can carefully catalog my personal media files, not use it as a dumping-ground of all files. On top of this, of course it does not work properly, so that when I had a new folder with 10 video files in a monitored location, only 8 of them would appear automatically, and I had to add the last two manually. Wow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s go back and discuss WMV. When you convert one type of media encoding to another, it&amp;rsquo;s called &amp;ldquo;re-encoding.&amp;rdquo; So one must re-encode any movie in Xvid of Divx format (e.g. all downloaded TV shows) into WMV. There is a program called TVersity that comes really close to making this problem disappear. What it does is let you add any movie files to its list, and this list appears on the Xbox under the Videos area. So one cool thing is that it&amp;rsquo;s simulating the media sharing feature of Media Player. But what&amp;rsquo;s even cooler is that it will serve the Xbox an on-the-fly re-encoded WMV stream instead of the original file. This lets you have lots of Xvid files around, but the Xbox can still play them. Here are the disappointments of this setup:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You cannot fastforward or rewind in a stream. So basically you can pause your videos, or stop them and restart from the beginning. That&amp;rsquo;s it. Not too flexible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My PC (an Athlon XP 2500+) is evidently too slow to do all this in real time, despite playing with the setttings. So there were always 5-10 pauses per half-hour show, of 30 seconds each, each of which ended up skipping over a few seconds of video.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this stage (I&amp;rsquo;m progressing chronologically through my experiments in this narrative), I decided I&amp;rsquo;d try to just re-encode a given season of a TV show we were watching all at once into WMV using some tool, and then stream these using media sharing. So I found a tool called Encode360 that has the Xbox in mind, and I started to re-encode. Here were the disappointments of this approach:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are three flavors of WMV. The best quality is offered by so-called WVC1, but to encode a 30 minute show in this format took about 90 minutes. Moreover, after doing two or three shows, Encode360 would crash, and so what should have finished in a day or so took me a week of restarting jobs before work and before going to bed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you use the lower levels of WMV quality, you have to up the bitrate to get watchable video. But bitrate is directly proportional to file size, and so a 300MB Xvid file would become a 1GB WMV file. And since I want to keep the Xvid original, that&amp;rsquo;s 1.3G per half-hour show!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s talk about Media Center. You can think of it as a special version of Media Player that looks great on a TV and is easy to navigate with a remote control. It connects to a Media Center PC which itself runs a very similar-looking full-screen interface. Basically the Media Center PC streams all its data to the Xbox, so it becomes another way to view videos, music and photos. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t really solve any of the above problems with encoding, since the Xbox still needs WMV format movies even inside Media Center. But if I were to re-encode all the movies myself (maybe by finding a better tool than Encode360) then maybe I could at least have a better organized interface for browsing playlists and having real Title metadata. Also, there&amp;rsquo;s a plugin for Media Center that does what TVersity does (re-encode to WMV on the fly), but it crashed Media Center the first time I tried it. I like the Media Center interface, and if it let me organize movies I guess that would make me happy. But I still need to do all that re-encoding work, which I&amp;rsquo;m not willing to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more item on Media Center. It also shares photos and music to the Xbox, but its whole metaphor for photos is just stupid old hard drive folders and filenames. We have tools like iPhoto on the Mac and Picasa on Windows now, that have transcended this old model by light-years. What about storing photos in albums? Or giving them Titles instead of filenames? Or giving them other metadata like tags and comments? None of this is in Media Center from what I could see. We have to keep everything organized by folder and filename, which is not where metadata should live. Lastly, if you use an iPod and buy music from iTunes, then the music sharing is not useful to you, since it can&amp;rsquo;t play protected iTunes music, nor can it see your iTunes playlists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transitioning now, I have two friends at work who swear by Media Center. When I complained about my woes with the Xbox, they couldn&amp;rsquo;t relate 100% because their setups are different in one key way: They have their PCs in their living rooms, directly connected to the home theater. They have so-called HTPCs (Home Theater PCs), and so they can play whatever video formats they want, since the Xbox is not involved. If you want one of these, then you need a new computer. But if you&amp;rsquo;re going to go to that trouble, why not get a Mac Mini, which has Front Row, a similar piece of software to Media Center. I decided to try this by installing Front Row on my Powerbook, hooking it up to the TV, and seeing what was possible. Here are the wins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can play any video file (MPEG, Xvid, Divx), since now you&amp;rsquo;re using a Real Computer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can play iTunes music, including using actual, real library sharing from the iTunes library on my PC (the main repository of music in our house)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can see my iPhoto library, which I don&amp;rsquo;t use since the photos are on our PC, so it&amp;rsquo;s not so useful to me, but iPhoto is better than flat folders and files, so it wins in principle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can add videos to iTunes and give them Title metadata rather than use filenames. I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to find out if I can make playlists of videos. To do any of this, you need to use QuickTime to make a so-called &amp;ldquo;reference movie&amp;rdquo;, which is a small file that a) can be added to iTunes, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t accept .avi files directly and b) refers to the original and plays it, saving the space of a full re-encoding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The interface is nice of course, but comparably nice versus Media Center&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can view video podcasts, something Media Player cannot do without third-party add-ins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a breakthrough when I tried it using my PowerBook. I still kept all the movie files on my PC, and used file sharing to play them over the network. If I buy an inexpensive Mac Mini, I can make it its own component in my home theater and use Front Row all the time. If you&amp;rsquo;re wondering where Apple TV fits into this, it would provide a &lt;em&gt;similar&lt;/em&gt; setup to a Mac Mini for less money, but it can only play MPEG4 and QuickTIme movies, which puts you in a re-encoding situation similar to the Xbox. But at least MPEG4 is a real open format with lots of tools available, unlike WMV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TiVo was a nonstarter by the way, since although it can connect to a PC to play files, it can only play TiVo MPEG2 files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, when it comes to recording TV shows over cable TV or satellite, you have another set of choices. Media Center and TiVo both do this, but not Front Row or Apple TV. If you want to record HD, you need to either buy a $2,000 HTPC or an $800 TiVo Series 3. When the Series 3 drops in price, I&amp;rsquo;ll consider getting one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amusingly bad web design</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2006-06-28-amusingly-bad-web-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2006 03:16:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2006-06-28-amusingly-bad-web-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I came across this site while looking for card tables. It made me laugh out loud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://greg.langmead.info/wp-content/my_images/bad_design.png&#34; alt=&#34;bad_design.png&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ShelfCentered.com</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2005-04-25-shelfcenteredcom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2005 04:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2005-04-25-shelfcenteredcom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the last couple of months, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a new side project that my wife, brother and sister and I came up with, called ShelfCentered.com. I haven&amp;rsquo;t posted about ShelfCentered.com as of yet, because honestly I suspect it might be a good enough idea to really become something good, and I want to protect us from competitors! For example, there are a couple of shareware programs out there already that do what we&amp;rsquo;re planning, and they&amp;rsquo;ve created some limited buzz, but so far no one has thought to put the idea online in a nice web site. I won&amp;rsquo;t go into detail just yet, but it&amp;rsquo;s hard to maintain a blog without mentioning the thing that&amp;rsquo;s my primary occupation outside work!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The burden has been on me to get the site off the ground, but once it&amp;rsquo;s to a certain point the rest of the family will be able to help out more. I&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling to get enough mental traction, but now I think I&amp;rsquo;m getting somewhere. As always, it was a combination of gathering the right set of tools, and being organized enough to start drawing some specifications. There was a longish period of experimentation with a particular application of Web Services as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the tools I&amp;rsquo;m using:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My PowerBook is the primary development machine, because it has the Unix environment that imitates our web host, and I can develop around the house. All the items below are installed both on my &amp;lsquo;Book and on our server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apache.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Apache&lt;/a&gt; (comes with Mac OS X)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.php.net&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PHP&lt;/a&gt; (comes with Mac OS X)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mysql.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MySQL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://smarty.php.net&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Smarty&lt;/a&gt;. This is the most interesting part. It will let me separate the display of the data on the site from the PHP code that fetches it from Web Services or the local database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.barebones.com/products/textwrangler/index.shtml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;TextWrangler&lt;/a&gt;. (This is only on my Mac.) This is the free version of BBEdit. It can parse PHP to give me a function popup, and has a great drawer feature where the files I&amp;rsquo;m working with are listed without window clutter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MathML</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2005-04-16-mathml/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2005 22:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2005-04-16-mathml/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My friend and former coworker, Robert Miner, has written an article about MathML in the latest issue of Notices of the American Mathematics Society, which you can &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ams.org/notices/200505/fea-miner.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;read online&lt;/a&gt; [pdf]. MathML is a standard XML representation of math notation and semantics, and has been adopted steadily ever since Robert co-created it in 1998.  When I worked at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dessci.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Design Science&lt;/a&gt; with Robert, MathML was becoming a major focus for the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was happy to see this article, because the academic math community is still very focused on TeX/LaTeX, which are fine as far as they go, but somewhat old-fashioned and limited compared to MathML.  TeX is strictly for presentation, for example, and conveys no semantic content. You couldn&amp;rsquo;t paste TeX into a computer algebra system, for example, and expect it to compute anything.  MathML is a better, more general solution, and has other benefits Robert covers in the article. One likely future application is the ability to index and search math formulas, something I began working on with Robert towards the end of my tenure at Design Science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope the math community becomes more aware of this technology and begins to adopt it. Nice work, Robert!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello from Clié</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2004-03-28-hello-from-clie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2004 21:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2004-03-28-hello-from-clie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m blogging this from my new Clié TH-55. It has wireless networking and a full web browser, plus email. I&amp;rsquo;m still looking fo a free instant messaging client.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hotspot</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2004-03-14-hotspot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2004 05:26:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2004-03-14-hotspot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m blogging this from a Starbucks in Hollywood, near the big shopping center called Hollywood &amp;amp; Highland. Alison is out with a friend nearby, so I decided to try out the Starbucks hotspot system. Works pretty well, but only for 24 hours &amp;ndash; next time I visit a Starbucks I&amp;rsquo;ll have to pay $6 for an hour, then 10 cents a minute afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New family additions</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-10-12-new-family-additions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2003 20:32:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-10-12-new-family-additions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve made two changes to my video game family. First, I bought a GameCube and a couple games (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gamespot.com/gamecube/adventure/legendofzeldathewindwaker/review.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Zelda&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gamespot.com/gamecube/action/viewtifuljoe/review.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Viewtiful Joe&lt;/a&gt;). Also, a friend with a vinyl cutter made a wood-grain applique for my Xbox. &lt;a href=&#34;https://greg.langmead.info/images/GregsTrueLoves.html&#34;&gt;Click to see the new family!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VisiCalc history</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-04-09-visicalc-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2003 05:59:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-04-09-visicalc-history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bob Frankston, co-creator of the original spreadsheet VisiCalc, has recently written down &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.frankston.com/?name=ImplementingVisiCalc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;a postmortem&lt;/a&gt;, 25 years later!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work category coming</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-04-08-work-category-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2003 04:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-04-08-work-category-coming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not that you care, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to merge in all my work content into a category, and see how it coexists with my main category.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beware of Bounceweb!</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-04-01-beware-of-bounceweb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 02:29:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2003-04-01-beware-of-bounceweb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Boy, Bounceweb threw us for a loop. Our site went down so hard that when it came back up, various files and directories were gone! They had to restore from backups, and even so there was a lot of work to do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So langmead.info seems relatively stable</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-08-14-so-langmeadinfo-seems-relatively-stable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2002 21:49:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-08-14-so-langmeadinfo-seems-relatively-stable/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So langmead.info seems relatively stable at the moment. As of now I have tried three hosting companies. This latest one strikes a good balance between price and features. They are having trouble installing PHPlib, which is needed for IMP, which is a web-based email client Alison wants. I might consider moving if they never get around to that (or upgrading to PHP 4.1, which would be just as good).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea here is that we have a home for family pictures, personal web sites (like this blog) and email. Mostly the last, because with mac.com going fee-based, and with the years passing and the number of email addresses I&amp;rsquo;ve used growing, it seems like a good time to have a &lt;em&gt;permanent&lt;/em&gt; email address, and paying for the domain and the hosting puts it under my control, so it can remain as permanent as &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; want it to.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good evening. Go-Gan is progressing,</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-03-14-good-evening-go-gan-is-progressing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2002 02:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-03-14-good-evening-go-gan-is-progressing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Good evening. Go-Gan is progressing, albeit slowly. It&amp;rsquo;s encouraging, though, to know that even though my job is largely programming, I still want to do it in the evenings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So the Paint-by-Numbers project, named</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-03-06-so-the-paint-by-numbers-project-named/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2002 02:05:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-03-06-so-the-paint-by-numbers-project-named/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So the Paint-by-Numbers project, named Go-Gan, is proceeding. Absolutely no interface has been coded yet, just the representation of the underlying puzzle. Tonight I&amp;rsquo;ll write the logic that creates the list of clues from a row or column of painted cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that&amp;rsquo;s done, I&amp;rsquo;m going to skip over the hardest part of all, and go to the user interface and Cocoa bits. The hard part is a feature where a player working on a puzzle can get a hint.  No matter what hinting system I eventually implement, they all rely on the computer being able to (secretly) solve a puzzle completely. Certain scenarios may not require the whole puzzle to be solved in order to give the hint, but the real underlying purpose of this project, besides learning Cocoa, is to figure out how to get a computer to solve a PBN from just the clues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I know are the ad-hoc rules that Alison and I apply to a PBN puzzle, but sometimes there are several speculative steps needed, which will require the computer to perhaps build a branching tree of decisions, in order to arrive at a contradiction in all but one path from root to leaves.  The most important principle, though, is the &amp;ldquo;more than half&amp;rdquo;, where a clue tells you there are &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; cells colored black in a space where fewer than &lt;em&gt;2n&lt;/em&gt; will fit. This allows you to fill in some of the middle squares, which then give you information about the columns.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m going to get started</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-03-04-im-going-to-get-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2002 02:03:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-03-04-im-going-to-get-started/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to get started today on a new piece of software. It will be a multipurpose &amp;ldquo;Paint by Numbers&amp;rdquo; application. Paint by Numbers is a puzzle game (I am not yet sure whether this name is a trademark or not) where you are presented with a blank rectangular grid of squares, usually about 20x20 or larger (the bigger it is, the harder it is). The goal is to reproduce the picture by deducing which squares should be colored. The clues are lists of numbers, one list for each row and one list for each column. Each number in the list is the tally for a consecutive run of colored squares. Visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://www02.so-net.ne.jp/~kajitani/cgi-bin/pbn.cgi/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this Japanese site&lt;/a&gt; for some examples to try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to write the app in Cocoa, the native environment for Mac OS X. In fact, this is just my excuse to learn Cocoa. When Apple computer bought Steve Jobs&amp;rsquo; company Next in 1995 (?), they did so to obtain the sophisticated Nextstep operating system. This became Mac OS X, and the then-revolutionary Nextstep programming framework became Cocoa. Tim Berners-Lee, the creator of HTML, HTTP, and the first web browser, wrote all of it using Nextstep. Why? Because it was easy, supposedly. I&amp;rsquo;ve explored it a little bit and I find it very exciting. It is easy in the sense that many things come for free, as in Java, but it is also hard in that it leaves me running to the documentation all the time &amp;ndash; once I commit the core of Cocoa to memory, this will disappear as well and it probably &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; seem easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll write the engine in C++, though, not Objective-C (the language you have to use to use Cocoa). The engine will include the abstraction of what a Paint-by-Numbers puzzle is, and the things the player can do to it. Actually wiring that up to a user of the app will be another layer, the user interface layer. This layer will listen to mouse clicks and whatnot, and will then call the appropriate message in the engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the most common way to interact with the puzzle will be to click on a square cell. When the click is heard, I will have to compute which square on the screen it was in, and therefore which abstract cell it is. Then, I will ask the abstract &amp;ldquo;paint by numbers cell object,&amp;rdquo; which is invisible to the user, to alter its state (turn it black, for example). Then, I&amp;rsquo;ll have the representation of the cell on the screen update accordingly, by asking the abstract cell what color it is now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still working out the architecture, but I should have some progress by day&amp;rsquo;s end.  I have some &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.economist.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Economist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; magazine reading to do too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m starting to understand the</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-02-28-im-starting-to-understand-the/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2002 01:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2002-02-28-im-starting-to-understand-the/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m starting to understand the news aggregator concept. It is the flipside of the blog. It addresses my earliest question about blogs: won&amp;rsquo;t everything I write just disappear into the void?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For non-geeks reading this, a news aggregator is a single program or web page that gathers together a generalized version of &amp;ldquo;headlines.&amp;rdquo; These can certainly include headlines, like from the BBC or AP wire. But they can also include postings or articles from any site that is &amp;ldquo;syndicated,&amp;rdquo; in a certain technical way, like this one is. You could ask your aggregator to pull in content from this very site, each time I update it. See how it provides the &lt;em&gt;audience&lt;/em&gt; with the corresponding tool to the &lt;em&gt;author&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt; tool of the blog?  By the way, this very product, Radio, includes a news aggregator and so marries the two tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My e-book obsession</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2001-11-09-my-e-book-obsession/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2001 01:29:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2001-11-09-my-e-book-obsession/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I HAVE AN E-BOOK OBSESSION! Did you know that? Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E-book is obviously short for electronic book. This sounds like a nineteenth century name for what it is: a computer file. In such a computer file are the contents of a book. For example, a Word document with Pride and Prejudice in it is an e-book. So is a plain text file of the same book, or a web page or any other format. The point is that the environment where the book is read is a digital computer environment. There are a few issues about e-books that I think are important. First, there is the issue of reading an entire book on a screen. Despite that, I am obsessed with reading e-books, so I will explain why. Finally, what does the future hold for e-books?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The detractors say that e-books are not going to be widely read until they appear on screens that are much fancier than our low-resolution devices of today. A typical computer monitor has fewer than 100 pixels per inch of screen, so the most precise unit of measurement is 1/100 inch. Book printing is done at a much higher resolution, and so the character shapes (&amp;lsquo;glyphs&amp;rsquo; in technical jargon) are very detailed lovely curves, compared to the collections of dots that you get on a screen. It is generally thought that it is easier to read the high-resolution text than the low. Moreover, monitors and laptop displays are backlit, where a book uses reflected light. Monitors blink at around 60-100 times per second, which can give you a headache (though laptop displays do not blink at all, which makes them more comfortable). All this adds up to a reading experience that tires your eyes pretty quickly. In the future, we may have &amp;ldquo;digital ink,&amp;rdquo; which is an umbrella term for a number of emerging technologies that work much more like a book. These would have a sheet of material that would feel like paper or plastic, but would be digital in that each page would have electrical current and a grid of extremely tiny pixels, such that the resolution was maybe as high as 1200 pixels per inch. Some sort of computer chip, maybe embedded right in the page, would turn pixels on and off and set them to different colors, to produce a document as lovely as a printed page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, so if reading electronic text is so awful, and can give you a headache, why do you read them? Well, my e-books don&amp;rsquo;t give me a headache. I read them on my Palm, and it neither blinks nor is backlit. The Palm screen works using reflected light just like page, or more to the point a digital watch. It has black LCD pixels on a light gray background, so it has high contrast and no flickering. When it&amp;rsquo;s dark, I do turn on the backlighting, and it indeed gives me a headache before too long. As for the pixellated fonts, they don&amp;rsquo;t bother me. I have a selection of fonts on my Palm and I have chosen ones that were very well designed to take advantage of the pixellation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is an art to making text readable at low resolution &amp;ndash; compare some of the fonts on your computer at small point sizes and see which ones you think had readability at small sizes as a design goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the problems I mentioned before don&amp;rsquo;t bother me. What&amp;rsquo;s so great, though? Why read an e-book instead of a paper book? E-books are one of those things that don&amp;rsquo;t make as much sense before you use them as they do after. Computers and the Internet required the same kind of transition, for example. But I can give you some of the reasons that reading books on my Palm lead to this je ne sais quoi. The main one is that the Palm holds several books. That means that without carrying anything extra around, I have several novels. (And the Palm itself is very slight and is always with me anyway, for notes and To Do&amp;rsquo;s and names and addresses and the like.) If I&amp;rsquo;m stuck in line at the bank, or on a bus, or waiting for Alison to find some pants at Old Navy, I can (and do) slip my Palm out of my pocket and resume reading right were I left off. I have one of the buttons on the front re-assigned to launching my e-book program, so that I can perform all of this with just my thumb. If you like reading, then the idea of bringing your books that much closer and having them that much more accessible will make sense to you, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another plus is the ability to read with one hand. I can use my thumb to scroll to the next page if I hold my Palm upside-down and rotate the display as well (screen orientation is an option in my e-book reader). This works great at meals, and when straphanging on public transportation. You can search for text too, which I&amp;rsquo;ve used to remind myself of past actions in the story, or to re-read a passage where a character was first introduced (oh, he&amp;rsquo;s her uncle). Finally, the backlighting is a boon for married folks. The dim light doesn&amp;rsquo;t disturb your bedmate, and so it solves the &amp;ldquo;reading in bed problem&amp;rdquo; for me. Like I said, though, it gets hard on my eyes within about 20 minutes. Your mileage may vary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re sold on e-books, let me warn you off a little bit. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to get them. If you want to see the best store there is, and it&amp;rsquo;s good but it&amp;rsquo;s no Amazon, then visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.peanutpress.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peanutpress.com&lt;/a&gt;. They are owned by Palm and they have a pretty large selection, six or seven of which I&amp;rsquo;ve bought and downloaded. I hope that the future brings great growth to this and other vendors. What&amp;rsquo;s to lose? They do a one-time translation from the electronic source of the printed book into an e-book, and they sell each copy for $6, without having to make any books. The economics are there, so it&amp;rsquo;s just the usual chicken-and-egg market size story: the market isn&amp;rsquo;t there until there are lots of customers, but customers aren&amp;rsquo;t drawn until there are lots of books. Peanutpress is forging the way by selling all these books into a tiny market. There are more e-publishing ventures than there were a couple of years ago, though. The publishing houses have set up some online e-book stores, but they seem mainly geared to books that don&amp;rsquo;t also get printed the old way. This give the impression that they are second-rate fare, not good enough to publish as &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; books. Still, this means they are giving a voice to authors that they can&amp;rsquo;t afford to publish any other way (presumably), and more voices is good (as long as they aren&amp;rsquo;t spewing crap).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have read a lot more than five or six e-books, though. I&amp;rsquo;ve read about 20 novels this way, and I&amp;rsquo;m reading one now with four more lined up. How did I do that? It&amp;rsquo;s pretty interesting, really. First I buy the book at a bookstore. I put it on my shelf and I never open it. Then, I go online (using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.limewire.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Limewire&lt;/a&gt; usually, which is a Gnutella client) and I type in the author&amp;rsquo;s name. Often a list of text files pops up, and sometimes even fancier formats like RTF (which has formatting and bold and italic fonts) or HTML. These are created by someone with a &amp;ldquo;book scanner,&amp;rdquo; which is a regular scanner plus a page feeder. They cut off the spine of a book and feed all the pages in. The software puts the images in the right order and does character recognition on it, and makes a text file. These are then distributed over the internet for folks to download. It&amp;rsquo;s exactly like the way music and movies are pirated online, and it violates all the same copyright laws. I don&amp;rsquo;t feel bad, though, because I buy the book and merely use this technique to &amp;ldquo;move it onto my Palm.&amp;rdquo; Am I bad for doing that? I can&amp;rsquo;t tell, but I certainly don&amp;rsquo;t feel bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me wrap this up by indicating some of the ideas that I consider to be at the fringe of e-books. Some will tell you that dedicated e-book readers like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gemstar-ebook.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Gemstar e-book&lt;/a&gt; are what e-books are about. These devices are crippled compared to a Palm or other handheld. They are too big, too expensive, and they control what content you can install. You cannot convert one of your own text files or web pages to an appropriate format and load it onto the Gemstar, like you can with a Palm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another non-e-book line of thinking are the Adobe E-book reader and the Microsoft Reader. These are programs for your laptop or desktop machine, and so they are lacking the two main requirements of e-books: portability and reflective screens. I can curl up on the sofa with a cup of coffee and my Palm. If I were a PocketPC user (like Palms only with a Microsoft operating system) I&amp;rsquo;d be very disappointed right now. You can get lots of books in the Microsoft Reader format, but only a subset of those can be used with the Pocket PC version of the Reader. I can&amp;rsquo;t understand why, unless it&amp;rsquo;s because they have hard-coded line breaks that don&amp;rsquo;t work on the smaller pocket-sized screen. But that&amp;rsquo;s not a good enough reason &amp;ndash; make the line breaking dynamic and get the books on the handhelds!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer geeks</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/1998-02-09-computer-geeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 1998 07:51:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/1998-02-09-computer-geeks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://greg.langmead.info/wp-content/uploads/2008/03/banner.gif&#34; alt=&#34;1998Banner&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note, this was written before I had a blog. I recovered it from the Internet Archive. Back in graduate school I had a “musings” section of my site and those essays are in the same spirit as this blog so I’ve added them with retroactive datestamps.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really feel that our society cannot sustain the &amp;ldquo;computer geek&amp;rdquo; model for very much longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, I&amp;rsquo;ll now have to describe what I mean by that model. It&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;m sure you&amp;rsquo;ve noticed, but probably never given much thought to. It&amp;rsquo;s bound to be the case that there are people who are more expert at any given job than others, and not long ago computers were hard for anyone to use, even experts. Therefore it&amp;rsquo;s not surprise that there are adults (but mainly kids) out there who are better than most at using computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I feel this edge will soften really soon, and perhaps disappear entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think some examples are in order. I work in a math department, and for years mathematicians have been into their email. That&amp;rsquo;s simply because mathematics is so specialized that the likelihood that all your favorite colleagues in your area teach at your school is nil. So, you need fast, cheap channells of communication open all the time, and email fits the bill ideally. At around the same time email was getting hot in math, so was TeX. TeX is a document typesetting system which allows us math folks to typeset our own papers and equations with completely professional appearance. It requires a fair bit of computing power, and it&amp;rsquo;s so esoteric that at first it was only to be found on UNIX workstations. (The sad pathetic story of UNIX, which sucks, will be the topic of at least one other essay at some point, I&amp;rsquo;m sure. What a joke.) So that&amp;rsquo;s two reasons to have UNIX around a math department. Running an FTP server to distribute your papers, which are now completely electronically-based is a third, and for some the computational power of C programs is a fourth. In more recent days, web surfing is a must, and so is a web server. If students can&amp;rsquo;t get their homework and solutions and grades online these days (at least at Columbia), they start complaining (especially at Columbia, I bet).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fine, so math departments have UNIX networks. Big deal. Well, you try running a UNIX system, even at home on your own PC or Mac, where you&amp;rsquo;re the only user. It&amp;rsquo;s hard. It&amp;rsquo;s hard mostly because UNIX sucks, but it&amp;rsquo;s hard nonetheless, and someone has to do it. It&amp;rsquo;s so hard, though, that to figure out how to do it is a &lt;strong&gt;full-time job&lt;/strong&gt;! (Man, does UNIX suck.) So, each department needs at least one individual whose responsibliity is to keep the system up and working smoothly, including the individual programs running on it like email clients and servers, or web clients and web servers. As people break the system (because it sucks and is impossible to figure out) this person has to deal with the offenders and fix the problems. It&amp;rsquo;s really a social job, requiring the monitoring of a large group of independent people. Sometimes technical announcements have to be made (&amp;ldquo;From now on, please don&amp;rsquo;t lpr a .dvi file on lw421&amp;rdquo;). Sometimes this person gets mad. And here is my point: what if this administrator gets so mad that they stop doing their job. What if they quit? Well, the entire operation of the department would be put in jeopardy. No one would get their email. At first they would be mad. &amp;ldquo;Hey, why is the damn email broken? For christ&amp;rsquo;s sake, do something!&amp;rdquo; Then they&amp;rsquo;d realize that the only person who knows how to fix it is gone. &amp;ldquo;Crap, Peter left.&amp;rdquo; They&amp;rsquo;re powerless. They&amp;rsquo;d realize that they were entrusting a large and important element of their working life to one individual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s too much power for one person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People need these technical programs working all the time. But they depend on one single individual person to do it. In some larger organizations, several people or a whole IS department may take care of it. But that means that those people can do something you can&amp;rsquo;t do yourself, even if you need it done now. It means that you have delegated responsibility for &lt;strong&gt;your&lt;/strong&gt; machine and &lt;strong&gt;your&lt;/strong&gt; email and &lt;strong&gt;your&lt;/strong&gt; work to another. If it breaks, you &lt;strong&gt;can&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong&gt; fix it, and they &lt;strong&gt;have to&lt;/strong&gt;. People won&amp;rsquo;t stand for that kind of balance of power for very long. How many secretaries out there have figured out how to fix their copiers because they can&amp;rsquo;t stand how long it takes for the real copy dude to show up, let alone do a decent job?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same principle applies here. I think people will gradually devote more of their time to learning how more complex computer operations are managed, such as networking and email. I think the software will get easier to use also, like it does in every other segment of the computer industry. The knowledge will decentralize. It won&amp;rsquo;t be a specialization anymore. Everyone will know how it works, just like people tend to know a little about how their car works, or how their washing machine works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, you may ask, what about plumbing? I don&amp;rsquo;t know how to fix my plumbing, and I use that all the time. In fact, I use it more than email (speak for yourself!). I don&amp;rsquo;t know how the insides of any of my home gadgets work, like my stereo, my TV, my phone, or even my computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good point. But computer software is somehow different, I think. So many people are using computer software these days, in so many incredibly complex ways, that something is very different about it. I think using software and email is like using the phone. It won&amp;rsquo;t be a big deal to restart your SMTP client or whatever, 5 years from now, because you just double-click this little icon, or select this menu entry. People are so comfortable with computers, that anyone who uses one today would be considered an expert four years ago. People know what GIFs are now, and how JPEGs can suck, so there&amp;rsquo;s a tradeoff. They know about 8-bit versus 24-bit color depth. They know how big 800x600 pixels is. They know how to defragment their hard drives. They know how SCSI works, and that it&amp;rsquo;s faster than IDE. They know that an en-dash and an em-dash are different typographically. They know what &lt;html&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/html&gt; means. They may even know what SGML stands for. Or the difference between a Postscript and a PDF file. These are extremely technical points, but some of us don&amp;rsquo;t see them that way anymore, because we literally work with them all the time. Computer technology is completely pervasive today, and will only get more so. Technical literacy is on the rise big time. And just in time for when your local guru gets fed up and quits. Maybe there won&amp;rsquo;t be IS departments in the future. Every working adult will know how to handle all that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They will probably know from age six.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
