<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Misc on Long Head</title>
    <link>https://greg.langmead.info/category/misc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Misc on Long Head</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 12:36:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://greg.langmead.info/category/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Smoothness</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2018-11-05-smoothness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 12:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2018-11-05-smoothness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post accompanies a pair of talks given at CMU in November 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Coming soon: my notes from the talk, and possibly a screencast.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Links&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Differential_structure&#34;&gt;Wikipedia article about differential structures&lt;/a&gt;, with a table of counts of exotic spheres.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bookstore.ams.org/fourman&#34;&gt;The Wild World of Four-manifolds&lt;/a&gt; by Alexandru Scorpan (2005), a simply wonderful resource about smooth structures in all dimensions, as a matter of fact.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://math.stackexchange.com/questions/1577985/smooth-manifold-m-is-completely-determined-by-the-ring-f&#34;&gt;A post that helped me&lt;/a&gt; with a proof about the ring of smooth functions determining a manifold.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.springer.com/gp/book/9783540562351&#34;&gt;A book that looks wonderful&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Natural Operations in Differential Geometry&lt;/em&gt; by Kolar, Michor and Slovak, 1993), but which I&amp;rsquo;ve had to pilfer rudely for information about the fully faithful embedding of smooth manifolds inside the category of commutative algebras.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lossless Lord of the Rings Blu-ray rip on iPad 3</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2012-03-24-lossless-lord-of-the-rings-blu-ray-rip-on-ipad-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 02:16:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2012-03-24-lossless-lord-of-the-rings-blu-ray-rip-on-ipad-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have seen what 1080p from a Blu-ray looks like on iPad 3, and it is something to behold. The detail and the colors are just beautiful. Over the last few days I&amp;rsquo;ve worked through the technical issues of ripping one of my Blu-ray discs and converting it losslessly to a format the iPad can play. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for every Blu-ray because they are not all encoded on the disc in H.264. For example, Blade Runner: The Final Cut is encoded in VC1, and so I had to transcode that (but it still looks amazing). But the LOTR Extended trilogy uses H.264 and so you can have perfection. The steps were:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lord of the Rings project to become a web site</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2011-06-15-lord-of-the-rings-project-to-become-a-web-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 01:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2011-06-15-lord-of-the-rings-project-to-become-a-web-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I &lt;a href=&#34;https://greg.langmead.info/?p=114&#34;&gt;have written previously&lt;/a&gt;, I created an annotated list of excerpts from &lt;em&gt;The Lord of the Rings&lt;/em&gt; to encapsulate the differences in the plot (and theme) from the Peter Jackson films. I was unhappy with the tabular format of a Google spreadsheet though, and so I cast around for other ways to present this information. My requirements were&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mathematics with MathJax</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2011-06-14-mathematics-with-mathjax/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 16:05:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2011-06-14-mathematics-with-mathjax/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a post to test the functionality of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mathjax.org&#34;&gt;MathJax&lt;/a&gt;. Just put a simple script tag in your header, pointing to a global copy of mathjax.js distributed via Amazon&amp;rsquo;s CloudFront content distribution network. After that, you can enter LaTeX or MathML directly in your posts and MathJax will render it into beautiful equations. Here is a favorite (from &lt;a href=&#34;http://arxiv.org/abs/hep-th/0210192&#34;&gt;my dissertation&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital conservation</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2010-09-30-digital-conservation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 13:38:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2010-09-30-digital-conservation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If I&amp;rsquo;m fixing a typo where I typed &amp;ldquo;loose&amp;rdquo; instead of &amp;ldquo;lose&amp;rdquo;, then is it less wasteful if I click inside and delete one of the &amp;ldquo;o&amp;quot;s, versus double-clicking the whole word and typing four brand new letters? If I do it the first way, it seems like I am reusing the existing four correct letters, so it seems less wasteful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ur-Quan Masters</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2010-09-26-the-ur-quan-masters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2010 19:34:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2010-09-26-the-ur-quan-masters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://greg.langmead.info/img/Screen-shot-2010-09-26-at-3.06.20-PM.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Screenshot of The Ur-Quan Masters&#34; src=&#34;https://greg.langmead.info/img/Screen-shot-2010-09-26-at-3.06.20-PM.png&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;I learned something new this weekend. First, I learned that one of my favorite childhood games, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Archon:_The_Light_and_the_Dark&#34;&gt;Archon&lt;/a&gt;, has some spiritual successors. The game designer Paul Reiche III, who designed Archon, went on to design other games from his studio Toys for Bob. I just learned all of this when I was listening to a podcast where some old timers like me were discussing the game Star Control 2, which Reiche designed and which was released for PC in 1992, and then on 3DO. It sounded like a great game, and given the Archon pedigree I was curious to try it out. Well the good news is that 3DO released the source code back to Reiche in 2002 and he made it open source, and so there are many ways to &lt;a href=&#34;http://sc2.sourceforge.net/downloads.php&#34;&gt;play the game today on modern hardware&lt;/a&gt; including Mac, PC, Wii, and Android. The name &amp;ldquo;Star Control 2&amp;rdquo; is trademarked and so this open source version is called &amp;ldquo;The Ur-Quan Masters.&amp;rdquo; Having played for 30 minutes, I was immediately drawn in to the accessible gameplay, the gentle introduction that gives you full control but subtly guides you to try new things, and the tinge of humor in the dialog. An abandonware success story!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Star Wars for Toddlers is a go</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2010-09-26-star-wars-for-toddlers-is-a-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2010 19:19:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2010-09-26-star-wars-for-toddlers-is-a-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finished editing Star Wars, and my 3-year-old loves it, and I feel guilt-free about showing it to her. There were some wrinkles during the process, so the current version is actually the third one I made (I&amp;rsquo;m REAL familiar with the movie now, at least around the problematic scenes). I ended up having success with the Mac-based tool &lt;a href=&#34;http://simplemoviex.com/SimpleMovieX/&#34;&gt;SimpleMovieX&lt;/a&gt;, and in fact it&amp;rsquo;s the first piece of software I&amp;rsquo;ve paid for in a long time (and it&amp;rsquo;s not cheap, $40). The free version is full-featured, but saving out the whole movie would have taken a couple of days because they deliberately slow down file saves in order to get you to pay. Still, I ended up liking that particular method of having a free trial, because it let me experiment with all the features over any number of weeks or months (which is sometimes how long it takes me to get my act together).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Star Wars for toddlers</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2010-09-11-star-wars-for-toddlers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2010 18:03:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2010-09-11-star-wars-for-toddlers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My daughter is 3, and her best friend is also 3. He has been shown the entire Star Wars trilogy already, and is in love with Darth Vader. So my daughter hears about it a lot, and is excited to see it too. Recently I showed her a couple moments from Episode 4, and she loved it. So I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to make a version of the movie that is appropriate for her. I&amp;rsquo;ll edit out everything I deem too intense or violent, and see how it goes. So far, I have a rip of the DVD, and I&amp;rsquo;m trying to get it into iMovie.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s hurry along the iPad gaming revolution</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2010-07-10-lets-hurry-along-the-ipad-gaming-revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2010 19:19:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2010-07-10-lets-hurry-along-the-ipad-gaming-revolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am so excited at the possibilities the iPad holds for gaming, especially strategy gaming. Others have voiced enthusiasm, but I think there&amp;rsquo;s another level or two of excitement that folks are missing. So let&amp;rsquo;s hasten the story along because I want to play these games. Let me convince you I&amp;rsquo;m right, and then you can go make some games for me. I&amp;rsquo;ll pay $50 for the games I have in mind. Do you hear me, Matrix, Paradox, Slitherine, Panther, Creative Assembly, SSG, Firaxis, Big Huge Games, TGW, Wizards, and friends?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tolkien project complete</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2010-07-10-tolkien-project-complete/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2010 17:58:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2010-07-10-tolkien-project-complete/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finished my project to annotate the differences between the book and movie version of LOTR. So I updated &lt;a href=&#34;http://greg.langmead.info/?p=114&#34;&gt;my earlier post&lt;/a&gt; to point to the finished product.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OK</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2010-03-30-ok/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2010 20:14:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2010-03-30-ok/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read a few theories about the origin of our expression &amp;ldquo;OK.&amp;rdquo; But I haven&amp;rsquo;t come across this one that occurred to me the other day. When you hold your hand in that gesture that means &amp;ldquo;OK&amp;rdquo;, you make a circle with your thumb and index finger. That&amp;rsquo;s an O, and your other three fingers sort of make a &amp;ldquo;K&amp;rdquo;. The middle finger is the vertical stem, and the other two fingers are the diagonal ones. Just a thought.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distance learning for the over-educated</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2010-03-24-distance-learning-for-the-over-educated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 02:51:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2010-03-24-distance-learning-for-the-over-educated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m definitely a &amp;ldquo;lifelong learner&amp;rdquo; type, always craving new courses, books, or ideas. I even love reading long computer game manuals for complicated games like Europa Universalis 3. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty easy to learn the beginning of a new field, because there are usually some audiobooks, Teaching Company courses, or online materials to introduce you to the main concepts. But what if you already know a lot about something, and you want to learn even more?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giving digital items is hard</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2009-12-08-giving-digital-items-is-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2009 20:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2009-12-08-giving-digital-items-is-hard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of a few things I like: books, audiobooks, music, movies, video games, iPhone apps. I consume these items on a variety of devices: Kindle, iPhone, PC, Mac, Xbox, PS3, Wii. Most of those platforms have a digital download mechanism in place for the software, e.g. you can download music or audiobooks from the iTunes store, Amazon or Audible. You can download movies from iTunes, Amazon, Xbox, or PS3. You download iPhone apps from iTunes. You can download Kindle books from Amazon. You can download many PC games from Steam. Some games are ONLY available for download. The consoles have their own built-in stores that use points or a credit card.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mac Moments: Not using paths</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2009-07-27-mac-moments-not-using-paths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2009 03:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2009-07-27-mac-moments-not-using-paths/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On my Mac, I had a movie in my Movies folder called &amp;ldquo;Sesame Street Season 1 part 1.m4v&amp;rdquo;. I dragged it to iTunes so I could play it there (for my daughter), and all was well. One day I wanted to move those old Sesame Streets into a folder called &amp;ldquo;old&amp;rdquo;, so I made the &amp;ldquo;old&amp;rdquo; folder and dragged that movie in, no big deal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lord of the Rings in 100 48 pages</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2009-07-19-lord-of-the-rings-in-100-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2009 18:12:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2009-07-19-lord-of-the-rings-in-100-pages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a huge fan of Peter Jackson’s movie versions of The Lord of the Rings novels. A HUGE fan. But I am also a fan of the books, which I have read several times, and which I have also done supplementary reading on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My interpretation of 42% pro-choice</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2009-05-18-my-interpretation-of-42-pro-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 02:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2009-05-18-my-interpretation-of-42-pro-choice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going way out on a limb here, so bear with me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;42% of Americans are pro-choice, according to a new Gallup poll, and 51% are pro-life. My response to this is: since so many Americans disagree with the pro-life stance, then we should stick with the neutral road, which is the policy to keep abortions legal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why is science important?</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2009-03-13-why-is-science-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2009 21:23:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2009-03-13-why-is-science-important/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was linked to this video today and really enjoyed it. I have never heard of Alom Shaha, but I hope to see more from him in the future.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/3531977&#34;&gt;Why is Science Important?&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/user1353157&#34;&gt;Alom Shaha&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nudge</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2009-02-24-nudge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 04:58:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2009-02-24-nudge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m reading an interesting book about economics, public policy, and psychology. It&amp;rsquo;s called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Nudge-Improving-Decisions-Health-Happiness/dp/014311526X%3FSubscriptionId%3D13D7MCZQKMM5E1WMY782%26tag%3Dshelfcentered-20%26linkCode%3Dxm2%26camp%3D2025%26creative%3D165953%26creativeASIN%3D014311526X&#34;&gt;Nudge&lt;/a&gt;. They make many interesting points that were completely new to me about the way people do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; behave in the rational manner modeled by the previous generation of economists. In fact, there are systematic biases in our decision-making that can be quantified and worked around by enacting sensible policies. The cover issues ranging from the Medicare prescription drug plan to 401k plans, to organ donation, to the environment. The ideas are presented clearly with lots of examples. Highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vista = Ick</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2009-01-12-vista-ick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2009 03:22:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2009-01-12-vista-ick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m so tired of living with Windows Vista. Especially when it comes to USB. Whenever I plug in a USB device that I&amp;rsquo;ve used a million times before, but I plug it into a different USB port, Vista goes into overdrive. &amp;ldquo;Searching for driver!&amp;rdquo; it exclaims in a balloon. The hard drive churns and churns for about two minutes. You can&amp;rsquo;t do anything else disk-intensive during this time, so basically you&amp;rsquo;re just waiting at this point. If you click the little tray icon that appears, it says &amp;ldquo;Searching for driver in installed locations&amp;rdquo; or something. Finally it&amp;rsquo;s done and it says &amp;ldquo;Canon digital camera.&amp;rdquo; No kidding, the one I plugged in yesterday? Congratulations. Maybe I should plug it into each port in my hub so that I can go through this once and then know that I&amp;rsquo;m safe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Freshness</title>
      <link>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2008-10-08-freshness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2008 20:06:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greg.langmead.info/posts/2008-10-08-freshness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love the feeling I get after I tweak what songs are on my iPhone. I added a composer (Mahler) and a Teaching Company course (about Mahler) because I finished listening to another course (about US relations with the Middle East). I added some Beatles album art and the latest Ben Folds album. It&amp;rsquo;s all freshened up and ready for new listening!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
